A Cinematic Event 50 Years In The Making
Apollo 11 is a documentary, history, drama film directed by Todd Douglas Miller.
A look at the Apollo 11 mission to land on the moon led by
commander Neil Armstrong and pilot Buzz Aldrin.
Self (archive footage), played by Neil Armstrong.
Self (archive footage), played by Buzz Aldrin.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Collins.
Self (archive footage), played by Walter Cronkite.
Self (archive footage), played by Bruce McCandless II.
Self (archive footage), played by Charlie Duke.
Apollo 11 is a 2019 American documentary film edited,
produced, and directed by Todd Douglas Miller.
It focuses on the 1969 Apollo 11 mission, the first
spaceflight to land humans on the Moon.
The film consists solely of archival footage, including 70 mm film previously unreleased to
the public, and does not feature narration, interviews, or modern recreations.
The Saturn V rocket, Apollo 11 crew (consisting of Buzz Aldrin, Neil Armstrong, and Michael Collins), and
Apollo program Earth-based mission operations engineers are prominently featured in the film.
The film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 24, 2019, and was
released theatrically in the United States by Neon on March 1.
It received acclaim from critics and grossed $15 million at the box office.
At the 4th Critics' Choice Documentary Awards, the film won a leading five awards (including Best Documentary Feature), and, at the 72nd Primetime Creative Arts Emmy Awards,
it won three awards (for editing and sound) out of five nominations, one of which recognized Aldrin and Collins' work capturing the Apollo 11 mission on film.
The film explores themes of moon, nasa, based on
true story, moon landing, space.
The tone is emotional.